<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>the leadership journey on Leadership Stoa</title>
    <link>https://yazerk.com/tags/the-leadership-journey/</link>
    <description>Recent content in the leadership journey on Leadership Stoa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 20018–2021, Yağız Erkan; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yazerk.com/tags/the-leadership-journey/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Leadership Journey - My New YouTube Channel</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-09-18-new-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-09-18-new-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;ive-been-an-explorer-in-the-leadership-and-management-universe-for-a-long-while-im-hoping-to-share-my-thoughts-with-you-using-the-audiovisual-medium-on-youtube&#34;&gt;I’ve been an explorer in the leadership and management universe for a long while. I’m hoping to share my thoughts with you using the audiovisual medium on YouTube..&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, folks! I just posted my &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/fAsl7OkHC_8&#34;&gt;intro video&lt;/a&gt; on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCegYuFzCpuV2ZkMswZP5TgQ&#34;&gt;new YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;. It explains the reasons why I decided to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in professional software development for 25 years, and in the last 15 years I’ve held various leadership roles. But I wasn’t always interested in leadership or management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to work in software development for two main reasons: I’ve always loved creating, and I noticed that software development gave me the same satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I also loved the fact that software industry provided ample learning opportunities. I was not going to run out of things to learn. My job was never going to be boring and stale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I knew I wanted to remain an individual contributor. I saw management as a necessary evil, at best. I probably wasn’t even very interested in distinguishing between leadership and management. I loved what I was doing. I was creating products that were useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, people were messier than computers, compilers and debuggers. So my having a leadership position happened somewhat reluctantly. I was wary. I distinctly remember that I was afraid of being stuck at a job where I didn’t learn much, and I was also afraid of losing the edge off my technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I discovered over time was simply amazing. Leadership and management was like a gate that transported me to a different universe with as much learning opportunities. It also allowed me to become a better person (and later a better parent). Some of those skills and concepts are definitely very close to my heart now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCegYuFzCpuV2ZkMswZP5TgQ&#34;&gt;The Leadership Journey&lt;/a&gt; YouTube channel I want to share a part of this passion with you, if you’re willing to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a life-long student, so I’m here and there not as an expert, far from it, but at best, as an explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in anything, please take what I’m saying with a healthy dose of skepticism, and think, and do some research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can stir your mind and gently provoke your thoughts I would be very happy. If I can inspire you, that would be the best gift I can get from this channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So please be generous with your comments and feedback. I’m not looking for compliments (though they are always nice to hear), but mostly for being challenged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining me in this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel profile picture: Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@fedotov_vs?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Vladimir Fedotov&lt;/a&gt; on [Unsplash]https://unsplash.com/s/photos/lamp?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel background picture: Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@musickid98?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Alfred  Aloushy&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/leadership?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
