<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hic Sunt Leadership</title>
    <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hic Sunt Leadership</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 20018–2021, Yağız Erkan; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yazerk.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Leadership Journey - My New YouTube Channel</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-09-18-new-youtube-channel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-09-18-new-youtube-channel/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;ive-been-an-explorer-in-the-leadership-and-management-universe-for-a-long-while-im-hoping-to-share-my-thoughts-with-you-using-the-audiovisual-medium-on-youtube&#34;&gt;I’ve been an explorer in the leadership and management universe for a long while. I’m hoping to share my thoughts with you using the audiovisual medium on YouTube..&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, folks! I just posted my &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/fAsl7OkHC_8&#34;&gt;intro video&lt;/a&gt; on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCegYuFzCpuV2ZkMswZP5TgQ&#34;&gt;new YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;. It explains the reasons why I decided to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in professional software development for 25 years, and in the last 15 years I’ve held various leadership roles. But I wasn’t always interested in leadership or management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to work in software development for two main reasons: I’ve always loved creating, and I noticed that software development gave me the same satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I also loved the fact that software industry provided ample learning opportunities. I was not going to run out of things to learn. My job was never going to be boring and stale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I knew I wanted to remain an individual contributor. I saw management as a necessary evil, at best. I probably wasn’t even very interested in distinguishing between leadership and management. I loved what I was doing. I was creating products that were useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In comparison, people were messier than computers, compilers and debuggers. So my having a leadership position happened somewhat reluctantly. I was wary. I distinctly remember that I was afraid of being stuck at a job where I didn’t learn much, and I was also afraid of losing the edge off my technical skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what I discovered over time was simply amazing. Leadership and management was like a gate that transported me to a different universe with as much learning opportunities. It also allowed me to become a better person (and later a better parent). Some of those skills and concepts are definitely very close to my heart now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCegYuFzCpuV2ZkMswZP5TgQ&#34;&gt;The Leadership Journey&lt;/a&gt; YouTube channel I want to share a part of this passion with you, if you’re willing to watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a life-long student, so I’m here and there not as an expert, far from it, but at best, as an explorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in anything, please take what I’m saying with a healthy dose of skepticism, and think, and do some research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I can stir your mind and gently provoke your thoughts I would be very happy. If I can inspire you, that would be the best gift I can get from this channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So please be generous with your comments and feedback. I’m not looking for compliments (though they are always nice to hear), but mostly for being challenged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for joining me in this journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel profile picture: Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@pavement_special?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Riccardo Annandale&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/idea?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Channel background picture: Photo by &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/@musickid98?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Alfred  Aloushy&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://unsplash.com/s/photos/leadership?utm_source=unsplash&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=creditCopyText&#34;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Issues - Podcast</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-03-05-authority-issues-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2021-03-05-authority-issues-podcast/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;best-way-to-spend-48-minutes-of-your-life-i-was-the-guest-at-the-62nd-episode-of-authority-issues-podcast-it-was-a-real-pleasure-to-chat-with-rachel-and-kendall&#34;&gt;Best way to spend 48 minutes of your life! I was the guest at the 62nd episode of Authority Issues podcast. It was a real pleasure to chat with Rachel and Kendall.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We talked about what I studied, how I started my career, my getting into management, my first leadship position, my mistakes, and many more...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://authorityissu.es/62&#34;&gt;Yaz Erkan (Pex) - Authority Issues - Episode 62&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managers Club Interview</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2019-01-29-managers-club-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2019-01-29-managers-club-interview/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;i-got-interviewed-by-vidal-graupera-of-managers-club-it-was-a-lot-of-fun&#34;&gt;I got interviewed by Vidal Graupera of Managers Club. It was a lot of fun.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.managersclub.com/yagiz-erkan/&#34;&gt;Interview with Yagiz Erkan, VP of Technology at Motive Retail&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to Better Stand-Ups</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2019-01-23-road-to-better-stand-ups/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2019-01-23-road-to-better-stand-ups/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;the-daily-stand-upscrumhuddle-is-one-of-the-most-used-and-abused-practices-of-many-agile-methodologies-you-need-a-simple-mind-shift-to-make-it-more-effective&#34;&gt;The daily stand-up/scrum/huddle is one of the most used and abused practices of many agile methodologies. You need a simple mind-shift to make it more effective.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stand-ups. Nightmare of some, frustrations of many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not that you have to practice scrum to have stand-ups, but here is how &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scrumguides.org/scrum-guide.html&#34;&gt;the Scrum Guide&lt;/a&gt; describes it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Daily Scrum is a 15-minute time-boxed event for the Development Team…
At it, the Development Team plans work for the next 24 hours…
…Here is an example of what might be used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did I do yesterday that helped the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What will I do today to help the Development Team meet the Sprint Goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I see any impediment that prevents me or the Development Team from meeting the Sprint Goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derived from the information above, most of the stand-ups wrongly end up with team members answering the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What did you do yesterday?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are you doing today?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you had any impediments?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the above excerpt says “here is an &lt;strong&gt;example&lt;/strong&gt;”. It doesn’t prescribe these three questions as a template to live by. This approach, just like any approach that seems dogmatic is against the basic agile principles, in which we continuously question our assumptions and practices in order to improve by making adjustments. Stand-ups are no exception.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;walking-the-board&#34;&gt;Walking The Board&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;… to inspect progress toward the Sprint Goal and to inspect how progress is trending toward completing the work in the Sprint Backlog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s change our point of view, and let’s do a story-driven stand-up. Instead of putting the focus on each team member one by one, let’s walk the story board from one end to the other and let’s make the stories talk. I like the right-to-left approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the team’s job is to minimize the time it takes for every work item to go from the left-most to the right-most point. Therefore the questions we ask during the daily stand-up should reflect that. &lt;em&gt;“How can we unblock this?”&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;“How can we help this test?”&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;“Can I help you with this?”&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;“How can we move this to ${next_stage}”&lt;/em&gt; are some of the questions that the team can ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;less-individualism--increased-team-ownership&#34;&gt;Less Individualism &amp;amp; Increased Team Ownership&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making the story the focal-point of the conversation also nurtures a culture of increased team ownership. It’s less about &lt;em&gt;“who’s doing what?”&lt;/em&gt;, and more about &lt;em&gt;“how can we help advance the stories to reach the sprint goal as a team?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lines between closing tickets individually and helping others close tickets get intentionally hazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Highly-effective teams don’t sprint individually. They carry the baton to the finishing line together. Effective daily huddles are a great way keep the team’s momentum at an optimum level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Monkeys - A Corporate Fable</title>
      <link>https://yazerk.com/posts/2018-03-05-angry-monkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yazerk.com/posts/2018-03-05-angry-monkeys/</guid>
      <description>
        
          &lt;h4 id=&#34;this-is-my-favorite-corporate-fable-its-moral-is-simple-but-it-is-very-easy-to-walk-right-into-it&#34;&gt;This is my favorite corporate fable. Its moral is simple, but it is very easy to walk right into it.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A group of scientists put five monkeys in a room, and in the middle they placed a stepladder that had a delicious banana on its platform. When a monkey climbed the ladder and got to the banana the scientists hosed down the remaining 4 monkeys.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;After a while the poor animals understood that they were going to get drenched if one of them attempted to get to the banana, so they lunged at the monkey that fell into temptation and beat it until it changed its mind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Finally, when the monkeys established a brute-force-controlled environment where no monkey attempted to go for the forbidden banana, the scientists replaced one of the monkeys with a new one. As the new monkey didn’t know anything about the disturbing ritual, it immediately tried to get to the banana. But its attempts faced the determined aggressive resistance from the other monkeys. After a while, battered and bruised, it learned that it was not allowed on the ladder.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time when the group found its behavioral equilibrium, the scientists replaced one of the original monkeys by a new one until none of the original monkeys were left in the room. The scientists didn’t need to use water anymore as the older members of the group never let the new monkey climb on the ladder. And every new member to the group met a brutal resistance, even from the newest members, which prevented the new monkey reaching the banana until the new monkey gave in without understanding the reasons behind the assaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the experiment, in the room remained five angry monkeys that didn’t let each other or a new one climb the ladder without really knowing why.*&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is closely related to something that most of us have experienced in various stages in our careers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question and understand the true purpose of the established processes before you follow them blindly.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

        
      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
